Elvis Ono Software Engineer

GitHub: Link to Github

Mobile: 07778833743 | Email: elvisonob@yahoo.com

Portfolio-website: www.elvisonob.com

United Kingdom

Available for onsite or Hybrid role

PROFILE SUMMARY

A technically proficient software developer with hands-on experience and solid foundation in React, JavaScript/TypeScript, and NodeJS. Possesses an excellent adaptability with a strong drive to master new tech stacks and explore new systems, and committed to bringing ingenuity to your organization.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

HTML/CSS REST and GRAPHQL API Creation.

JavaScript NodeJS TDD(Cypress).

TypeScript ExpressJS Currently building a React Project with

React Git/Github a NodeJS Backend

Redux SQL and NoSQL Database

CAREER EXPERIENCE

Software Developer - Boolean, UK

2023 - Present

- Design, develop, and maintain front-end user-centric interfaces using React, and server-side architecture with NodeJS, to meet evolving business requirements that increased user engagement by 30%.
- Collaborate and review with cross-functional teams including Technical Lead, Product, Design, Marketing
 and Business Analysts, to ensure seamless integration of APIs, new features and actively providing
 solutions to ensure systems are fit for purpose.
- Organized and led a scrum team that turned user requirements into quality software with excellent scalable, reliable, and secure performance which improved efficiency by 35%.
- Participate in all aspects of the software development lifecycle, including design, coding, documentation, requirements gathering, debugging and TDD using Cypress and Jest.
- Active participation in stand-ups, code reviews, Agile, kanban, CI/CD, branching, and pull requests.

IT Operations Support - TrustFord Group, UK

2023 - 2024

- Managing and resolving IT Queries.
- Creating and maintaining documentation, including user manuals, technical specifications, and process documentation, and contributing to knowledge sharing initiatives within the IT team.
- Managing relationships with external vendors and service providers, evaluating vendor products and services, and negotiating contracts and agreements.
- Analysing data to identify trends, patterns, and insights that can inform decision-making and drive business value, and preparing reports and presentations to communicate findings.

PROJECTS

Quiz Application <u>Link to Live-view</u> <u>Link to Github</u>

- A Quiz application with five straightforward questions where users can select an answer, and at the end of the questions, a detailed summary is provided.

- Technology used: React, React Hooks: useEffect, useState, useRef, useCallBack

Shopping App

<u>Link to Live-view</u> <u>Link to Github</u>

- A Full stack application which optimizes user's interaction, and items can be added to cart, removed, filtered by use-by dates, and purchased.
- Technology used: React, NodeJS, ExpressJS

EDUCATION HISTORY

Full Stack Software Development – Software Academy, UK Certificate of Completion	2021- 2022
Robert Gordon University, Aberdeen UK Master of Science, Engineering	2020 - 2021
University of Benin Master of Science, Electrical and Electronics Engineering Second Class Upper (2:1)	2016 - 2018